export const questions = [
  {
    category: "sports",
    question: "Ryder cup is related to which sports?",
    options: ["Polo", "Golf", "Badminton", "Tennis"],
    answer: "Golf",
  },
  {
    category: "sports",
    question:
      "In which of the following sports/ games the term Interference is used?",
    options: ["Golf", "Chess", "Squash", "Table Tennis"],
    answer: "Chess",
  },
  {
    category: "sports",
    question:
      "The word “Agricultural shot” is known to be used sometimes in which among the following sports?",
    options: ["Cricket", "Hockey", "Golf", "Polo"],
    answer: "Cricket",
  },
  {
    category: "sports",
    question:
      "Which of the following is awarded to individuals for promoting education, culture, development and peace through sport?",
    options: ["Olympic Cup", "Olympic Laurel", "Olympic Town", "Olympic Order"],
    answer: "Olympic Laurel",
  },
  {
    category: "sports",
    question:
      "Where are the headquarters of International Hockey Federation located?",
    options: ["Lausanne", "Berlin", "Amsterdam", "London"],
    answer: "Lausanne",
  },
  {
    category: "arts",
    question:
      "which state Government is to organise the tribal cultural festival called ‘Zo Kutpui’?",
    options: ["Assam", "Sikkim", "Meghalaya", "Mizoram"],
    answer: "Mizoram",
  },
  {
    category: "arts",
    question: "Madhavpur Mela is a famous attraction of which state of India?",
    options: ["Rajasthan", "Gujarat", "Madhya Pradesh", "Haryana"],
    answer: "Gujarat",
  },
  {
    category: "arts",
    question:
      "Udyanotsav is a famous Indian occasion, that makes which place open for general public for nearly a month?",
    options: [
      "Rashtrapati Bhavan",
      "Parliament House",
      "Secretariat Building",
      "Coronation Park",
    ],
    answer: "Rashtrapati Bhavan",
  },
  {
    category: "arts",
    question:
      "Which Indian city was recently certified formally as a World Heritage site by UNESCO?",
    options: ["Varanasi", "Ahmedabad", "Jaipur", "Nagpur"],
    answer: "Jaipur",
  },
  {
    category: "arts",
    question:
      "Which state is set to host the Hornbill Festival this month, which was originally celebrated in Nagaland?",
    options: ["Assam", "Tripura", "Mizoram", "Meghalaya"],
    answer: "Tripura",
  },
  {
    category: "history",
    question: "Who presided First Buddhist Council?",
    options: ["Mahakassapa", "Vasumitra", "Moggliputra Tissa", "Sabakami"],
    answer: "Mahakassapa",
  },
  {
    category: "history",
    question: "Who took the title of Vatapikonda ?",
    options: [
      "Narsimhavarman I",
      "Simhavishnu",
      "Mahendravarman I",
      "Nandivarman II",
    ],
    answer: "Narsimhavarman I",
  },
  {
    category: "history",
    question:
      "Which among the following rulers is often described as ‘the first empire builder of Indian History’?",
    options: [
      "Dhanananda",
      "Mahapadmananda",
      "Bimbisara",
      "Chandragupta Maurya",
    ],
    answer: "Mahapadmananda",
  },
  {
    category: "history",
    question: "The Kalinga war was fought in which year of Ashoka reign?",
    options: ["6", "7", "8", "9"],
    answer: "8",
  },
  {
    category: "history",
    question:
      "In context of Mauryan administration, who was regarded as the ‘Chief treasury officer’?",
    options: ["Samaharta", "Paura", "Sannidhata", "Karmantika"],
    answer: "Sannidhata",
  },
  {
    category: "physics",
    question:
      "Which among the following orbits are more prone to harms of space debris or space Junk in comparison to others?",
    options: [
      "Polar Sun Synchronous Orbit",
      "Low Earth Orbit",
      "Geosynchronous orbit",
      "Geostationary Orbit",
    ],
    answer: "Geostationary Orbit",
  },
  {
    category: "physics",
    question:
      "Which among the following provides potential energy to an object?",
    options: [
      "Its momentum",
      "It’s position",
      "It’s acceleration",
      "It’s shape",
    ],
    answer: "It’s position",
  },
  {
    category: "physics",
    question:
      "Speed of light will be maximum in which of the following mediums?",
    options: ["Water", "Kerosene", "Flint Glass", "ChaDiamond"],
    answer: "Water",
  },
  {
    category: "physics",
    question: "The frequency range of Ultra High Frequency (UHF) is __?",
    options: [
      "3 to 10 Megahertz",
      "3 to 30 Megahertz",
      "300 to 3000 Megahertz",
      "300 to 30000 Megahertz",
    ],
    answer: "300 to 3000 Megahertz",
  },
  {
    category: "physics",
    question: "Which of the following is correct about Gravitational force?",
    options: [
      "It is always attractive in nature",
      "It is always repulsive in nature",
      "It may or may not be attractive in nature",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "It is always attractive in nature",
  },
];
